# MARIAM DARCHIASHVILI

**Graphic Designer** 

# **CONTACTS:**

The Netherlands

+31 (0) 6 245 09 969 komnen.info@gmail.com

#### **ABOUT:**

Avid graphic designer and visual artist, with a degree in Graphic Design from The Royal Academy of Arts, The Hague (KABK). An organised hard-worker and quick-learner; with interests in typography, printed matter and curation, but always open for a new experience.

My inspiration for personal projects lays in music, senses, language, philosophy and dark aesthetics, which I often try to incorporate in my work both theoretically and visually.

Believer in power of simplicity, reason and beauty of Classical Art.

#### **SELECTED EXPERIENCE:**

#### OPEN DAY FOR GRAPHIC DESIGN DEPARTMENT AT KABK

/Project management, Communication and Organisation November 2019 - January 2020, The Hague, KABK

#### OJALESHI - WINE LABEL IDENTITY FOR KOLHIDELI GROUP

/Design

October 2019, Tbilisi

#### KABK GRADUATION FESTIVAL - EXHIBITION

**/Design and Research, Exhibition Design**July 2019, The Hague, KABK

#### STEFAN SCHÄFER DESIGN & RESEARCH STUDIO - INTERNSHIP

/Design and Research

September 2018 - November 2018, Amsterdam

### THE GROVE DESIGN HOTEL - FREELANCE DESIGNER

/Design

April 2018 - August 2018, Tbilisi

#### VISUAL IDENTITY FOR KOAN HOSTEL TBILISI

/Design

April 2018 - Novermber 2018, Tbilisi

#### AMNESTY INTERNATIONAL - 50TH ANNIVERSARY - GROUP SHOW

/Design and Communication

April 2018, Amsterdam, Amsterdam Theatre

# FREELANCE DESIGNER FOR FA DEPARTMENT AT KABK

/Design and Communication

Exhibition posters, Newsletter, Open Day Identity of 2018

September 2017 - June 2018, The Hague, KABK

#### CONSOLIDATING SOUND AND IMAGE

/Lecture & Workshop

October 2017, Moscow, Sfera Education

#### VISUAL IDENTITY FOR SFERA EDUCATION

/Design

September 2017 - present, Moscow, Sfera education

#### **BALANCE BY STRUGGLE**

/Curation and Exhibition Design

September 2017, The Hague, Gemeentemuseum

# **PORTFOLIO:**

#### www.komnen.com

www.behance.net/Komnen www.the-dots.com [Mariam Darchiashvili] www.linkedin.com/in/komnen

#### **EDUCATION:**

# British Higher School of Art and Design / Art&Design Pre-Foundation

September 2013 - May 2014, Moscow

#### Royal Academy of Art (KABK)

/Graphic Design (BA)

September 2014 - July 2019, The Hague, The Netherlands

#### LANGUAGES:

- Georgian [Native]
- English [Fluent]
- Russian [Fluent]
- French [Pre-Intermediate] (J'apprends vite)

#### SKILLS:

- HONESTY
- SOFT SKILLS

/Fluent communicative and organisational skills; Sharp capacity for collaboration, team leading and critical reflection.

- STRONG CREATIVE WRITING SKILLS
- ADOBE

/Fluent in use of most software; Illustrator, InDesign, Photoshop, Premiere Pro, Audition and After Effects.

- TYPOGRAPHY

/Proficient in type design and calligraphy. Fluent use of Glyphs.

- PRINTING TECHNIQUES

/Familiar with Riso printing, silkscreen printing and letterpress.

- WEB DESIGN

/Intermediate use of HTML and CSS.

- 3D - Basic knowledge of Unity and Blender.